Guide to the George Harmon Knoles Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
George Harmon Knoles papers
1920-1994
SC0328
Knoles, George Harmon
15 Linear feet
Professional and personal papers of Stanford University professor of American history.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of George H. Knoles, 1986, 1993, 1998, 2002.
Information about Access
Letters of recommendation from accessions 1985-097 and 1986-022 are restricted; contact the University Archivist for more information. Otherwise the collection is open for research. Materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Biography
George Knoles was a distinguished professor of History at Stanford University. Dr. Knoles received two degrees from (then) College of the Pacific, an A.B. in 1928 and an M.A. in 1930. He joined Stanford as an instructor in history in 1937 and received his Ph.D. in history from Stanford in 1939. During World War II he was a Lieutenant in the Navy serving with the Pacific Fleet and in preparing Naval history after the War. In 1946 he rejoined Stanford rising to become Chairman of the History Department and the Margaret Bryrne Professor of American History before his retirement in 1972. Professor Knoles' field was American history. He has written extensively on American political, intellectual and cultural history, His major publications include The Presidential Campaign and Election of 1892, The Jazz Age Revisited, and The New United States: A History Since 1896. With fellow Professor Rixford Snyder he co-wrote Readings in Western Civilization, which was widely used in American universities in the study of western civilization. During 1950-52 and 1956, Professor Knoles went to Japan with a small group of Stanford professors to teach American history. In the years following he maintained many personal and professional relationships with Japanese scholars. He was a Fulbright Distinguished Lecturer in Japan in 1971. He was a popular teacher and established strong relationships with his students. These relationships with students continued after they left Stanford. Two of the many ways he served the University was as a speaker at alumni functions and as a field judge for Stanford Track Meets.
Scope and Content of Collection
Collection contains correspondence, memoranda, minutes, lecture notes, syllabi, manuscripts, photographs, and other papers pertaining to Knoles' academic career at Stanford, Stanford's overseas campuses, particularly those in Japan, the Institute of American History, his publications, and his work with the Associates of the Stanford University Libraries. There is extensive correspondence with other historians and students. Correspondents include Harold W. Bradley, Rixford K. Snyder, Thomas A. Bailey, John Foster Dulles, Frank Friedel, John F. Kennedy, Michio Murayama, Allan Nevins, E. E. Robinson, Arnold Toynbee, Gordon Wright, William and Eleanor Bark, John Gange, J. E. W. Sterling, and Max Savelle. Also included are several files on student unrest at Stanford in the 1970s and an audiotape of John Dewey speaking on philosophy at Cooper Union, New York, December 7, 1941. The personal papers within the collection include extensive correspondence, 1920s-1994, his Naval logs and records, 1942-45, and his World War II letters, 1944-46.
Access Terms
Bradley, Harold Whitman.; Dewey, John, 1859-1952.; Gange, John.; Robinson, Edgar Eugene, 1887-1977; Savelle, Max, 1896-; Snyder, Rixford K., (Rixford Kinney), 1908-; Stanford University. Department of History.; Stanford University. Institute of American History; Stanford University. Libraries. Associates; Phonotapes.; Photoprints.; Stanford-Tokyo University Seminars.; United States--History--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Original Accession, Accession ARCH-1985-097
  This accession includes administrative and professional correspondence, 1933-76; personal correspondence, 1930-76; course files; and Stanford-Tokyo Seminar records, 1961-68.
  - University General, 1937-1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - University General, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - University General, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - University General, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - University General, 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - University General, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - University General, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - University General, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - University General, 1967-1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Stanford-Tokyo Seminars, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10-12)
  - Stanford-Tokyo Seminars, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - Stanford-Tokyo Seminar Outlines, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Stanford-Tokyo Seminar Correspondence, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - Stanford-Tokyo Seminars, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Stanford-Tokyo Seminars, 1955-1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Keio-Stanford Summer Program, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
  - Stanford in England (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Stanford in France (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Professor Harold Bradley (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
  - Professor Rixford Snyder (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
  - Stanford Bookstore (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Mississippi Valley Historical Association, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Fulbright Japan (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Publishing-Henry Holt (Box 4, Folder 2-8)
  - Publishing-Stanford University Press (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Illustrations for "Readings in Western Civilization" (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Publishing-Letters of Permission (Box 4, Folder 11-13)
  - Publishing-Free Press (Box 5, Folder 1-6)
  - Passages from Mark Twain (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Book Royalty Accounting (Box 5, Folder 8-11)
  - History Course Outlines (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - History Course Exams (Box 6, Folder 3-6)
  - History Course Syllabus (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - Lecture Notes (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - American Studies Association (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
  - International Center (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - History Department, 1933-1945 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - History Department, 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 7-9)
  - History Department, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
  - History Department, 1950-1952 (Box 7, Folder 12-14)
  - History Department, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - History Department, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
  - History Department, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
  - History Department, 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 7-9)
  - History Department, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - History Department, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - History Department, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - History Department, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 13-14)
  - History Department, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 15-16)
  - History Department, 1965-1967 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - History Department, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 3-5)
  - History Department, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 6-8)
  - History Department, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - History Department, 1971-1976 (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
  - Obituaries (Box 9, Folder 12-13)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Political Commentaries, 1970's (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - History of the US Navy Fleet Command, 1941-1945 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
  - US Naval History Program (WWII) (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1940 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
  - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
  - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 3-5)
  - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 6-8)
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 9-11)
  - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 4-6)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 7-9)
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 11-12)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 18)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1986-022
  This accession includes administrative and professional files, 1967-80, and material on student unrest at Stanford of the late 60s to early 70s.
  - Black Student Issues (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Committee on Libraries (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
  - Correspondence, 1976-80 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - David Potter - information re biography and bibliography (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - David Potter - drafts of Knoles' bibliography of Potter's works (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - H. Bruce Franklin: press releases, memos, clippings, 1971-72 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Historical Pamphlets, including E. E. Robinson's "Faith and the University" delivered at Stanford Aug. 3, 1941, 1941-72 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - History Corner Dedication (1980) (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - History Course Outline and Notes (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - History of Western Civilization Course (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Inauguration of President Truman, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Japan Fullbright (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Kalamazoo College Presidential Inauguration, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Stanford-Keio Summer Exchange Report (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Student Unrest - AEL (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Student Unrest - Encina Hall (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Student Unrest - General (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Student Unrest - History Department (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Student Unrest - ROTC (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Student Unrest - SRI (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - University, 1967-72 (Box 3, Folder 7-10)
  - Audio tape: John Dewey on philosophy, 7-Dec-41 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1998-045
  This accession includes correspondence files of the Associates of the Stanford University Libraries, 1975-87; and administrative files pertaining to university affairs, 1942-83.
  - Associates of Stanford University Libraries, correspondence, 1975-77 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Associates of Stanford University Libraries, correspondence, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Associates of Stanford University Libraries, correspondence, 1979-80 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Associates of Stanford University Libraries, programs, 1978-79 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Associates of Stanford University Libraries, programs, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Associates of Stanford University Libraries, programs, 1985-87 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Pacific Coast Branch of AHA, Book Award Committee, 1972- (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Historical Society (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Stanford-in-Germany, 1972-73 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - University affairs, 1942-63 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - University affairs, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - University affairs, 1966-75 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - University affairs, 1976-80 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - University affairs, 1981-83 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2002-292
  This accession includes extensive personal correspondence, 1920s-94; correspondence and military papers from his World War II service, 1942-46; files pertaining to the Associates of the Stanford University Libraries, 1974-82; and an album and photographs from the Tokyo-Stanford Seminars, 1950-60.
  - Correspondence, 1920-1994
    - Bark, William and Eleanor, 1941-44 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bark, William and Eleanor, 1952-81 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bradley, Harold, 1942-44 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bradley, Harold, 1957-81 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Dockstader, Fred, 1941-42 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Gange, John, 1937-78 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Hawaii Loa College, 1971-82 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1945-66 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Savelle, Max, 1941-47 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Savelle, Max, 1953-79 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Snyder, Rixford, 1942-45 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Snyder, Rixford, 1946-52 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Snyder, Rixford, 1954-80 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Sterling, Wally, 1942-48 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Trent, Ted, 1937-43 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Trent, Ted and Ruth, 1946-53 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Trent, Ted and Ruth, 1954-80 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Personal correspondence and memorabilia, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Personal correspondence and memorabilia, 1930-32 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Personal correspondence and memorabilia, 1933-35 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Personal correspondence, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Personal correspondence, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Personal correspondence, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Personal correspondence, 1939-40 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Personal correspondence, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Personal correspondence, 1942 Jan-Jun (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Personal correspondence, 1942 Jul-Dec (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Personal correspondence, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Personal correspondence, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Personal correspondence, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Personal correspondence, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Personal correspondence, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Personal correspondence, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Personal correspondence, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Personal correspondence, 1950 Jan-Jul (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Personal correspondence, 1950 Aug-Dec (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Personal correspondence, 1951 Jan-Jul (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Personal correspondence, 1951 Aug-Dec (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Personal correspondence, 1952 Jan-Jul (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Personal correspondence, 1952 Aug-Dec (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Personal correspondence, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Personal correspondence, 1954 Jan-Jul (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Personal correspondence, 1954 Aug-Dec (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Personal correspondence, 1955 Jan-May (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Personal correspondence, 1955 Jun-Dec (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Personal correspondence, 1956 Jan-Jun (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Personal correspondence, 1956 Jul-Dec (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Personal correspondence, 1957 Jan-May (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Personal correspondence, 1957 Jun-Dec (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Personal correspondence, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Personal correspondence, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Personal correspondence, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Personal correspondence, 1961-62 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Personal correspondence, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Personal correspondence, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Personal correspondence, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Personal correspondence, 1966-67 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Personal correspondence, 1968-69 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Personal correspondence, 1970-71 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Personal correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Personal correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Personal correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Personal correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Personal correspondence, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Personal correspondence, 1977 Jan-Apr (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Personal correspondence, 1977 May-Dec (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Personal correspondence, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Personal correspondence, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Personal correspondence, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Personal correspondence, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Personal correspondence, 1982 Jan-Jun (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Personal correspondence, 1982 Jul-Dec (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Personal correspondence, 1983 Jan-Jun (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Personal correspondence, 1983 Jul-Dec (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Personal correspondence, 1984 Jan-Jun (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Personal correspondence, 1984 Jul-Dec (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Personal correspondence, 1985 Jan-Apr (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Personal correspondence, 1985 May-Oct (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Personal correspondence, 1985 Nov-Dec (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Personal correspondence, 1986 Jan-May (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Personal correspondence, 1986 Jun-Dec (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Personal correspondence, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Personal correspondence, 1988 Jan-May (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Personal correspondence, 1988 Jun-Dec (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Personal correspondence, 1989 Jan-Aug (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Personal correspondence, 1989 Sep-Dec (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Personal correspondence, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Personal correspondence, 1991 Jan-May (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Personal correspondence, 1991 Jun-Dec (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Personal correspondence, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Personal correspondence, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Personal correspondence, 1994 Jan-Jul (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Personal correspondence, 1994 Aug-Dec (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Personal correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - World War II records and correspondence, 1942-1946
    - Navy - official papers, 1944-45 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Navy - logs kept by Knoles, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Navy - photos (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Navy - official records envelope (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Navy - correspondence, 1942-44 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - World War II letters, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - World War II letters, 1945 Jan-Apr (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - World War II letters, 1945 April - May (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - World War II letters, 1945 June - July (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - World War II letters, 1945 Aug-Oct (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - World War II letters, Pearl Harbor, 1945 Dec-1946 Mar (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - World War II, Hawaii, memorabilia (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Personal and miscellaneous papers, 1915-1985
    - Borel Collection: correspondence and documents, 1980-85 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Notes of auto trip to California by Barker family, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Personal financial records, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Personal, miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Photographs, 1928-1980 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Stanford ephemera (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Ephemera, non-Stanford (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Associates of the Stanford University Libraries (ASUL), 1974-1983
    - ASUL correspondence etc., 1975-76 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - ASUL Colin Franklin on mezzotints, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - ASUL correspondence: Yosemite and John Muir, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - ASUL correspondence etc., 1977 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - ASUL William F. Barlow on book collecting, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - ASUL correspondence etc., 1978-79 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - ASUL programs, 1977-78 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - ASUL programs, 1976-77 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - ASUL programs, 1975-76 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - ASUL programs, 1974-75 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - ASUL Steinbeck programs (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - ASUL W. Morris tour, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
    - ASUL records, 1974-75 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - ASUL records, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - ASUL records, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - ASUL records, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - ASUL records, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - ASUL records, 1980-82 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - ASUL membership lists (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - ASUL Sacramento tour, 1976-77 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - ASUL program file, 1975-78 (Box 9, Folder 6-8)
    - ASUL Southern California excursion, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - ASUL Southern California excursion, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - ASUL records, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - ASUL English library tour, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 4-7)
    - ASUL records, 1979-80 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - ASUL records, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - ASUL records, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - ASUL records, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - ASUL ephemera (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Tokyo-Stanford University Seminars, 1950-1960
    - Album signed by Japanese students, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Photos from album, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Pamphlets from album (Kokichi Mikimoto and His Pearls; The Constitution of Japan) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "To our teacher, Prof. George H. Knoles" - card signed by students, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Photographs, 1950-51 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Photographs, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 6-7)
    - Photographs, 1956, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Tokyo-Stanford University Seminars in American Studies (bound copy of Issue No. 4 of The Bulletin of the Center for American Studies of the University of Tokyo), 1981 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Restricted Files, Accessions 1985-097 and 1986-022
  - Letters of recommendation, 1937-1980 (Box 1)
  - Letters of recommendation (Box 2)